Guide to the Russell and Sigurd Varian Papers
Stanford University Libraries.
- Sigurd F. Varian Papers, 1904-1972; Series 2
  - Professional Papers
    - Patent Records
      - Record of invention for rectangular resonator diaphragm, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Printed patents, 2,311,685 to 2,493,046 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Printed patents, 2,514,428 to 2,682,623 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Printed patents, 2,789,250 to 2,958,004 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Patents not by Sigurd F. Varian: 2,466,095 and 2,241,306 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - Data on Sigurd F. Varian's patents (3x5 cards) (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Subject Files
      - Aircraft engines, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - ARINC AEEC Subcommittee on Flight Recorders, minutes, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Engineering data, 1941-1948 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Klystron Research Group, minutes, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Metals: notes and miscellaneous items, 1934-1938 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - Metals: charts and drawings, 1927-1938 and undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - Metals: reports, 1944-1949 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - Metals: procedures, 1930-1944 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - Metals: reprints and articles, 1937-1944 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - Metals: commercial catalogs and lists (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Microdrill (Teletronics Lab), notes and drawings, 1944-1947 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Microdrill (Teletronics Lab), financial and legal papers, 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Miscellaneous reports and drawings, not by Sigurd F. Varian (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Outlook for Nuclear Securities, Baxter International Economic Research Bureau, circa 1955 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Varian Associates
      - Board of Directors, minutes, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Miscellaneous records (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Organization charts, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Personal Papers
    - Correspondence
      - Outgoing, 1917-1918 and earlier but undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Outgoing, circa 1918 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Outgoing, 1922 January-May (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - Outgoing, 1922 Jun-Dec (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - Outgoing, 1923 and circa 1924 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Outgoing, 1924 and circa 1924 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - Outgoing, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - Outgoing, 1926 Jan-Jun (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - Outgoing, 1926 Dec and circa 1926 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - Outgoing, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - Outgoing, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - Outgoing, 1929 Jan-Aug (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - Outgoing, 1929 Jul-Dec (Box 3, Folder 19)
      - Outgoing, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - Outgoing, 1931 and circa 1931 (Box 3, Folder 21)
      - Outgoing, 1932-1933 and circa 1933 (Box 3, Folder 22)
      - Outgoing, 1934-1935 (Box 3, Folder 23)
      - Outgoing, 1941-1942 (Box 3, Folder 24)
      - Outgoing, 1956-1958 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      - Outgoing, 1959-1960 (Box 3, Folder 26)
      - Outgoing, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 27)
      - Outgoing, undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
      - Outgoing, drafts of letters (Box 3, Folder 29)
      - Outgoing to Russell Varian, 1928-1947 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Outgoing to Winnie Varian, circa 1932-1935 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Outgoing to Winnie Varian, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - Incoming, A - K (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Incoming, L - Z (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Incoming, unidentified (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Incoming from Winnie Varian, 1930-1934 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - Incoming from Winnie Varian, 1935-1937 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - Incoming and related papers re: donation to Puerto Vallarta Hospital (Mexico), 1961-1963 (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - Incoming and related papers re: Mexican property and affairs, 1960-1962 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - Incoming and related papers re: oil ventures, 1954-1958 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Writings (Autobiographical)
      - My pets at home, 1904-1911 (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - Autobiography as a pilot, pp. 2-39 (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - Autobiography as a pilot, pp. 40-79 (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - Autobiography as a pilot, pp. 80-199 (Box 4, Folder 15)
      - Autobiography as a pilot, pp. 120-159 (Box 4, Folder 16)
      - List of chapters and miscellaneous notes (Box 4, Folder 17)
      - "Regular run to Panama" (Box 4, Folder 18)
      - Manaqua earthquake (Box 4, Folder 19)
      - Badger fight (Box 4, Folder 20)
      - The Pilot rambles (Box 4, Folder 21)
      - Miscellaneous revisions (Box 4, Folder 22)
      - Trip to Merida Yucatan (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Tampico (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - The Canal (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - Salvador during storm (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Stories and incidents in Panama (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Veracruz (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Forced landing (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - "There Was No Law" (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - "There Was No Law" - final form (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - "There Was No Law" - multilith masters (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - Flabob Airport, Opelika traffic control (Box 5, Folder 11)
      - Flight to Tabasco and Villa Hermosa (Box 5, Folder 12)
      - France Field (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - The General and Carmen (Box 5, Folder 14)
      - Los Angeles (Box 5, Folder 15)
      - Miscellaneous stories and Mexican map of route from Torreon to Durango, (1931) (Box 5, Folder 16)
      - Tejeria (Box 5, Folder 17)
      - "They Said Nothing" (Box 5, Folder 18)
      - Outline, story (mss) (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Miscellaneous drafts number 1 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Miscellaneous drafts number 2 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Miscellaneous drafts number 3 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Miscellaneous drafts number 4 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Miscellaneous drafts number 5 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Miscellaneous drafts number 6 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - Miscellaneous drafts number 7 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - Miscellaneous drafts number 8 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - Miscellaneous drafts number 9 (Box 6, Folder 10)
      - Miscellaneous drafts number 10 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      - Miscellaneous drafts number 11 (Box 6, Folder 12)
      - Writings re World War II flying, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Biographical Materials
      - Biographical, 1956-1966 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      - Financial papers, 1955-1959 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous Papers
      - Clippings from Sigurd Varian's notebook (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - "Murmurs," Barlow Sanitarium, June 1927 (Box 6, Folder 17)
      - Sloniger, Jerry, "Tequila and the Solid Gold Airmail," Private Pilot, April 1972 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Additional Papers
    - Clippings (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Varian Associates Records, 1948-1988; Series 3
  Correspondence, reports, minutes, financial records, memoranda, newsletters, publications, and other records.
  - General Records
    - Annual Reports, 1953-1979 (Box 1)
    - Annual Reports, 1980-1988 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Board of Directors, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Board of Directors, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Board of Directors, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Campagnie Generale de Telegraphie Sans Fil, catalogue, circa 1949 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Chronology of Varian Associates, 1948-1959 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Campagnie Generale de Telegraphie Sans Fil, correspondence, 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Campagnie Generale de Telegraphie Sans Fil, reports with translations (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Company philosophy, objectives, and management functions, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Compass Distinguished Achievement Award, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1948-1949 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1952-1957 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1958 Jan-Mar (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 1958 Apr-Jun (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 1958 Jul-Dec (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1959 Jan (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1959 Feb-Apr (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1959 May-Dec (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1963-1982 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Death of Russell H. Varian, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Death of Russell H. Varian, newspaper obituaries, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Death of Russell H. Varian, newspaper obituaries (photocopies) (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Death of Sigurd F. Varian, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Death of Sigurd F. Varian, newspaper obituaries, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Dedication of new facilities, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Early company brochures and statements, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Edward L. Ginzton Laboratory (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Employees: handbooks and miscellany, 1951-1974 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Employees service recognition banquets, 1973-1980 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Expansion planning committee, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Experimental detection of metallic contaminants in aircraft engine oil; final report, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Financial statement, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Financial statement, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Financial statement, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Financial statement, 1979-1982 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - General considerations for the improvement of the Klystron art (2 cc), 1950 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Ginzton, Edward L., "Microwaves," Science, April 1958 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Ginzton, Edward L., speeches, and memorabilia, 1966-1969, 1958-1984 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - "High-power UHF-TV Klystron," by the V. A. engineering staff, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Historical development of electronics in Palo Alto area, unsigned remarks for ground-breaking ceremony (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Hycon Manufacturing Company, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Investment reports; Dean Witter & Company, 1955-1957 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Investment reports; Merrill Lynch, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Klystron advertisements (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Magnetron-VacIon Pump, report, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Management Advisory Board, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Management conference, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Memos to employees and stockholders, 1951-1955 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Memos to employees and stockholders, 1956-1959 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Memos to employees and stockholders, 1961-1982 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Memos to shareholders, 1953-1986 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Miscellany (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Nuclear magnetic resonance instruments, 1954-1962 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Open houses, programs, 1956-1977 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Organization and Compensation Committee, 1956-1957 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Organization chart, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Packard, Martin, "The Varian Story,", 1980 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Patents, miscellaneous items (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Perham lease agreement, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - President's Planning Committee, 1958-1959 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Profit-Sharing Retirement Plan, 1956-1957 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Profit-Sharing Retirement Plan, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Reflex Klystron, Type X-13, tentative data, circa 1951 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - RETMA Industry Observer Group, tour of March Air Force Base, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Security analysts meetings, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Security clearance matters (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - S-F-D Laboratories, Inc. (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Shareholders meetings, 1952-1959 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Shareholders meetings, 1961-1969 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Shareholders meetings, 1970-1988 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Simplified theory of the ground speed indicator, typescript report, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Sperry Gyroscope Company, statement of royalties due Leland Stanford Junior University, 1952-1958 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Stock records, 1948-1954 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Stock records, 1955-1959 and undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Technical Policy Committee re: tunnel diode, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Ten Year Anniversary, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Varian and the vacuum business, typescript report (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Publications
    - Varian Associates Directories, 1952-1978 (Box 6)
    - Varian Associates Magazine, 1956-1963 (Box 7)
    - Varian Associates Magazine, 1964-1974 (Box 8)
    - Varian Associates Magazine, 1975-1988 (Box 9)
    - Varian Associates Magazine (4 Volumes), 1956-1971 (Box 19)
    - News-Note, 1953-1964 (Box 10, Folder 1-11)
    - News-Note, 1965-1974 (Box 11, Folder 1-10)
    - News-Note, 1975-1982 (Box 12, Folder 1-8)
    - News-Note, 1983-1988 (Box 13, Folder 1-6)
    - Varian Associates News-Letter, 1949-1956 (Box 13, Folder 7-9)
    - Catalogs (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Directory of products and sales offices (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - General brochures on Varian Associates (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Historical and biographical publications (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Instrument Division, technical information (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Klystron, historical (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Klystron catalogs and advertisements (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Medical products (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Product announcements and advertisements (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Spectroscopy (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Thomson-Varian (France) (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Tube Division News, 1971-1973 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Varian at a Glance (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Varian Network, 1987 Aug 21 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Press releases, 1956-1967 (Box 15, Folder 1-6)
    - Press releases, 1968-1979 (Box 16, Folder 1-11)
    - Press releases, 1980-1982 and undated (Box 17, Folder 1-4)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Clippings, 1948-1982 (Box 18, Folder 1-17)
    - Clippings, undated (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Additional Records
    - Clippings (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Klystron - clippings (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Klystron - clippings (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Klystronic Wonder [sheet music] (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Klystron boys [clipping] (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Letter from W.W. Hansen to D.L. Webster re Klystron research, 1939 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Hansen/Webster - re early Stanford University Physics Department (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Sperry Gyroscope/Board of Trustees agreement, 1938 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Varian Associate ledgers, vol. 1-vol.3, 21.1; 1 microfilm reel(s) (Box 21)
    - Varian Associate ledgers, vol. 4-vol.7, 21.2; 1 microfilm reel(s) (Box 21)
- Dorothy Varian Papers, 1930-1988; Series 4
  Correspondence, research files, and interviews pertaining to her biography of Russell and Sigurd Varian; correspondence, text of talks, articles, and other papers pertaining to Castle Rock Park, Varian genealogy, Varian Associates, and environmental issues.
  Dorothy Varian earned her A.B. in economics and business administration at the U of C at Berkeley in 1928. She pursued a career in advertising in the Bay Area prior to her marriage to Russell Varian in 1947, whom she had met on a Sierra Club trip. She served on the initial Board of Directors of Varian Associates and was its treasurer until 1951.
  Mrs. Varian was an active conservationist; with colleagues Doris Leonard and George Collins, she cofounded Conservation Associates in 1960. Their fundraising efforts helped create the Alaska wildlife Range, Point Reyes National Seashore, and Montana de Oro State Park. The Association also worked with the Varian Foundation and Sempervirens Fund to expand the Castle Rock State Park, originally envisioned by Russell Varian.
  - Biography Of Russell and Sigurd Varian
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1950-1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Incoming correspondence: Cowell, Henry and Sidney, 1962-1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Incoming correspondence: Ginzton, Ed, 1960-1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Incoming correspondence: Harrison, Aileen Dickson, 1960-1962 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Incoming correspondence: Jenkins, Dick, 1959, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Incoming correspondence: A - D (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Incoming correspondence: E - H (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Incoming correspondence: I - T (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Incoming correspondence: U - Z (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Incoming correspondence: re death of R. H. Varian, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Incoming correspondence: biographical dictionary entries on RHV, 1960-1965 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence of others relating to the Varians (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Letter to Russell Varian after his death, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Transcripts of interviews with Dave Davidson, and Leonard Schiff, 1961, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Transcript of interview with George Harrison, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Transcript of interview with David Webster, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Notes by Artemus Ginzton concerning Russell Varian (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Notes from a conversation with Anne Hadden (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Packard, Martin, "The Varian Story,", 1980 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Notes by Carl Schoder concerning the Varians, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Notes by Wenonah Varian concerning R. H. Varian (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Reminiscences of David Webster concerning the Klystron (photocopy) (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Typescript sources: Agnes Varian's diaries, 1895-1899; draft of, April 19, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Typescript sources: Agnes Varian's diaries, 1895-1899; draft of, May 13, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Typescript sources: letters of Agnes and John Varian to Ansel Adams, 1930 and 1931 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Typescript sources: scrapbook of Sigurd Varian (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Typescript sources: R. H. Varian poem (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Typescript sources: R. H. Varian, letter to Henry Cowell, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Typescript sources: license between Bloch, Hansen, and Varian Brothers, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Typescript sources and drafts: Russell's childhood (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Typescript sources and drafts: Palo Alto days, 1904-1911 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Typescript sources and drafts: life in Halcyon, 1910s (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Typescript sources and drafts: the 1920s (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Typescript sources and drafts: summaries of Eric Varian's letters, 1920s - 1930s (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Typescript sources and drafts: Humble Oil, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Typescript sources and drafts: the 1930s (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Typescript sources and drafts: television lab, 1931-933 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Typescript sources and drafts: letters of Russell, Sigurd and Winnie Varian, 1930s (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Typescript sources and drafts: letters, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Typescript sources and drafts: letters of Russell Varian, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Typescript sources and drafts: Russell and Sigurd as working/creative partners (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Typescript sources and drafts: Russell's ideas on creativity and invention (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Typescript sources and drafts: Russell and the wilderness (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Draft: John and Agnes Varian (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Draft: life at Halcyon (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Draft: Russell at Stanford University (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Draft: Farnsworth/Philco television research, 1931-1933 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Draft: biographies of Sigurd and Russell Varian (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Dorothy Varian's anecdotes about Russell Varian (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Research notes on Palo Alto, 1903-1915 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Research notes on Halcyon, 1914-1920 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Research notes on the family (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Research notes on Nan Duggan (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Research notes on Sigurd Varian (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Research notes on television research (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Research notes, miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 28-32)
  - Castle Rock Memorial
    - Ansel Adams, Portfolio IV: text by Dorothy Varian, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Brochures, articles, and clippings (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence and lists of subscribers, 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Report on the Castle Rock Project, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Text of Dorothy Varian's talk at fund-raiser, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Genealogy
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1974-1981 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Incoming correspondence: Bartholf, Howard E., 1974-1978 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Incoming correspondence: A - Z, 1959-1981 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Family dates and history (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Genealogical sources: Irish Varians (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Genealogical sources: New York Varians (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Genealogical sources: Varians in the Roman Empire (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Genealogical sources: general (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Stanford University
    - Varian Foundation grant to Economics Department: outgoing correspondence, 1960-1965 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Varian Foundation grant to Economics Department: incoming correspondence, 1960-1965 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Russell H. Varian Laboratory of Physics: outgoing correspondence and stock records, 1959-1961 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Russell H. Varian Laboratory of Physics: incoming correspondence, 1959-1961 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Russell H. Varian Laboratory of Physics: prospectus and press release (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Russell H. Varian Laboratory of Physics: Ed Ginzton dedication speech, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Russell H. Varian Laboratory of Physics: newspaper clippings (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Varian Associates
    - Correspondence, 1959-1974 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1977-1979 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1980-1988 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Notes and outline of a talk on Varian Associates history, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - "Early Days at Varian," talk, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Text of a talk on Varian history, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous and Personal Papers
    - Correspondence re royalties for Sig and Winnie Varian, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - "Dr. Russell Harrison Varian," unsigned, undated biography (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - "Education in Palo Alto and Its Oldest School," typescript article, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Ginzton, Artemus, draft of letter to Virginia and Ansel Adams (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Ginzton, Edward L., statement on death of Russell Varian, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Homing pigeons, photocopy of article by Charles Walcott, et. al., 1979 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - John O. Varian and Henry Cowell, typescript copy of article, typescript copy of article by Frederick Whitney (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Obituary for Agnes Varian, rough drafts, circa 1935 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Dorothy Varian, personal correspondence (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Remarks to WESTCON, Dorothy Varian (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Resource Center for Women, award to D. Varian, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Statement by Dorothy Varian before Senate Committee on S-4028 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Resume, Dorothy Varian, circa 1982 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Songsheet (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - IEEE Transactions on Microwave Theory and Techniques, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Varian; Twenty-Five Years, 1948-1973, by Dorothy Varian (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Additional Papers
    - Clippings (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-1993-078
    - House electrical data (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Observatory (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Sierra Club Columbia River Trip (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, news clippings (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Alaska trip, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Blue Water Charter (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Children's Trust; Codicil of Will (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Stock records and correspondence (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Will of George Russell Varian and related material (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Arroyo Grande Ranch property, miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Notes re Arroyo Grande Ranch (financial) (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Arroyo Grande Property (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Homestead High School Commencement, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, Wenonah Varian (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Sheila - property transfer, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 16)